<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spanish on Sonia Hamilton - Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog2.snowfrog.net/tags/spanish/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spanish on Sonia Hamilton - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog2.snowfrog.net/tags/spanish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks for Learning Foreign Languages</title>
      <link>http://blog2.snowfrog.net/2013/12/11/tricks-for-learning-foreign-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog2.snowfrog.net/2013/12/11/tricks-for-learning-foreign-languages/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;get by&lt;/em&gt; in a few foreign languages (Spanish mostly, some Portuguese and French). People&amp;rsquo;s first response to this is &amp;ldquo;oh that sounds so hard&amp;rdquo; quickly followed by &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going to learn languageX next year&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As if learning is a language is something you can quickly tick off your bucket list, to be followed by &amp;ldquo;go sky diving&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;see the Pyramids&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;walk Kokoda&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s always more to learn in a foreign language, and sitting down and doing grammar and exercises is &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;boring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Here are a few tricks I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;music:855c0023b1954a46e74a7147312c52c3&#34;&gt;Music&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Music is the easiest one - listen while you&amp;rsquo;re driving or working and just &amp;ldquo;pick up&amp;rdquo; phrases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what music to listen too? The latest hip-hop full of street slang isn&amp;rsquo;t going to help you&amp;hellip; I search for &amp;ldquo;top 100 albums languageX&amp;rdquo; and start from there. Older ballad-based music is usually best - the equivalent of Neil Diamond or Simon and Garfunkel in English. Sure your foreign friends will wrinkle their nose at your &amp;ldquo;music for oldies&amp;rdquo;, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;films:855c0023b1954a46e74a7147312c52c3&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Films&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foreign films are another good tool, especially when you &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; want to learn street slang. But the trick is to download the subtitles &lt;em&gt;in the foreign language&lt;/em&gt; rather than English subtitles, and &lt;em&gt;slow down the dialogue&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, one of my favorite films is &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elite_Squad&#34;&gt;Tropa de Elite&lt;/a&gt; (Brazilian Portuguese). Lot&amp;rsquo;s of fast dialogue and street slang. So I download the Portuguese subtitles from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.subtitleseeker.com/&#34;&gt;subseeker.com&lt;/a&gt;, load them into VLC, and set the playback speed to 80%. Instant enjoyable learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the subtitles aren&amp;rsquo;t synched with the film - tools like &lt;a href=&#34;http://home.gna.org/subtitleeditor/&#34;&gt;subtitleeditor&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://gnome-subtitles.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;gnome-subtitles&lt;/a&gt; can help you fix them up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;news:855c0023b1954a46e74a7147312c52c3&#34;&gt;News&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First thing in the morning don&amp;rsquo;t read the news in English, read it in your new language; for example I regularly read &lt;a href=&#34;http://elpais.com/&#34;&gt;El Pais&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sinembargo.mx/&#34;&gt;Sin Embargo&lt;/a&gt; (Spanish). The good thing about news is that you probably already have a general idea of world news, so you can get the jist of the article even if you miss a few sentences. And the language in most newspapers is usually pretty easy (about year 10 level), so it&amp;rsquo;s going to be easier than reading a novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learn-related-languages:855c0023b1954a46e74a7147312c52c3&#34;&gt;Learn Related Languages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My languages (Spanish, Portuguese and French) are latin-based languages. So learning in one of these languages often helps in the other languages. For example last night at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brazilian_jiu-jitsu&#34;&gt;BJJ&lt;/a&gt; training I asked my Brazilian instructor how you say &amp;ldquo;too late&amp;rdquo; in Portuguese (as in &amp;ldquo;you should&amp;rsquo;ve gone for that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Armlock&#34;&gt;armbar&lt;/a&gt;, but too late!&amp;ldquo;). He said that it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://translation.babylon.com/portuguese/demorou!/&#34;&gt;demorou&lt;/a&gt;!&amp;ldquo;, which is the same verb as in Spanish (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spanishdict.com/translate/demorar&#34;&gt;demorar&lt;/a&gt;). And not a phrase as in French or English &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.bab.la/dictionary/french-english/trop-tard&#34;&gt;trop tard&lt;/a&gt;/too late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you were good in Japanese, Korean and Mandarin would be easier languages to pickup than (say) Russian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;have-fun:855c0023b1954a46e74a7147312c52c3&#34;&gt;Have Fun&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Languages are fun once you get past the boring beginner stuff. All those new films to watch, all that new music, new food, new ways of looking at the world. Happy learning and &amp;ldquo;que te vaya bien&amp;rdquo; (good luck in Spanish).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flamenco Guitar Masterclass at Instituto Cervantes</title>
      <link>http://blog2.snowfrog.net/2009/10/17/flamenco-guitar-masterclass-at-instituto-cervantes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog2.snowfrog.net/2009/10/17/flamenco-guitar-masterclass-at-instituto-cervantes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I attended the second &lt;a href=&#34;http://sidney.cervantes.es/en/culture_spanish/culture_spanish.htm&#34;&gt;cultural activity&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://sidney.cervantes.es/en/default.shtm&#34;&gt;Cervantes Institute&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; a Flamenco Guitar Masterclass put on by a giant of the flamenco world &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oscarherrero.com/&#34;&gt;Óscar Herrero&lt;/a&gt;, with the assistance of David Rasko and students from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sydneyguitars.com.au/&#34;&gt;Sydney Spanish Guitar Studio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a large number of attendees (about 50) as well as many guitars, and we all had a great time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Óscar talked us through a brief history of flamenco and explained how a flamenco guitar differs from a classical guitar. He then demonstrated the playing techniques that give flamenco it&amp;rsquo;s distinctive sound &amp;ndash; the &lt;a href=&#34;http://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alzap%C3%BAa&#34;&gt;alzpúa&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rasgueado&#34;&gt;rasgeados&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golpe_(guitar_technique)&#34;&gt;golpes&lt;/a&gt;, as well as showing us a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.esflamenco.com/product/en33669381.html&#34;&gt;flamenco metronome&lt;/a&gt; that allows guitarists, dancers and singers to practice by themselves (very different from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metronome&#34;&gt;normal metronome&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; it has all the different beats like Sevillanos, Siguiriyas, etc). Then the best part &amp;ndash; Oscar would give a little improvisation based on the technique and pure music would flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I grew up we were all forced to learn a classical instrument at school &amp;ndash; piano, violin, flute or (classical) guitar, along with several &amp;lsquo;real&amp;rsquo; foreign languages (French and Latin for me). I learnt guitar, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t fun &amp;ndash; hours of practice and study each day, exams and formal auditions &amp;ndash; enough to put you off music for life. But learning the guitar got me interested Spanish (all the footnotes were in Spanish), and hearing Óscar and the students play has got me thinking about playing the guitar again &amp;ndash; Olé!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Class at Instituto Cervantes</title>
      <link>http://blog2.snowfrog.net/2009/10/15/first-class-at-instituto-cervantes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog2.snowfrog.net/2009/10/15/first-class-at-instituto-cervantes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Spanish Language Institute (&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Instituto_Cervantes&#34;&gt;Instituto Cervantes&lt;/a&gt;) has just opened in &lt;a href=&#34;http://sidney.cervantes.es/en/culture_spanish/culture_spanish.htm&#34;&gt;Sydney&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Institute has a similar role to that of  the French Alliance Francaise &amp;ndash; to encourage the spread of Spanish language and culture throughout the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night was the first night of the advanced class &amp;ndash; we started late as none of us had thought to order our textbooks and the poor teacher had to improvise, but there was also an opening of an exhibition of Peruvian photography so we had red wine and tapas on our break and then proceeded to have a great time in the second half of the class (all typically Spanish).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, onto the homework. At these more advanced levels we study the finer and more cultured aspects of the language, including of course slang and idioms. For example, my first homework question &amp;ndash; what is this word x? One of them is worth a lot (&amp;ldquo;worth an x&amp;rdquo;), two of them means brave (&amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;ve got to have 2 x&amp;rsquo;s to do that&amp;rdquo;),  if you have 3 of them you don&amp;rsquo;t give a damn (&amp;ldquo;it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter 3 x&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo;), and a lot of x&amp;rsquo;s means really difficult (&amp;ldquo;getting it cost me a 1000 pairs of x&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo;). There are many other uses for the word x, and it is of course one of the most widely used words in the Spanish language &amp;ndash; cojones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frikipedia.es/friki/Cojones&#34;&gt;Frikipedia&lt;/a&gt; tells me, &amp;ldquo;cojones (balls) are a mechanism of masculinity created to relieve stress . they&amp;rsquo;re made of two oval forms covered with skin that is impermeable to alpha rays . it is believed that cojones emit a magnetic radiation that attracts the spherical objects used in sports .&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if Japanese or German classes are like this..?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vino y vinagre</title>
      <link>http://blog2.snowfrog.net/2009/03/14/vino-y-vinagre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog2.snowfrog.net/2009/03/14/vino-y-vinagre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a pleasant surprise last night &amp;ndash; well pleasant for the Spanish spea[]&lt;a href=&#34;http://pipka.org/blog/2009/03/12/iceland-software-resellers-being-screwed-by-disappearing-clients-and-licensing-contracts/&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;king part of my brain, anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vnc server on Ubuntu has been called &lt;strong&gt;vino&lt;/strong&gt; for ages &amp;ndash; Spanish (and Italian, Portuguese, etc) for wine. Ubuntu Hardy (8.04) onwards has a nice new application called &lt;strong&gt;Remote Desktop Viewer&lt;/strong&gt; (Applications, Internet) &amp;ndash; allows you to easily manage multiple vnc sessions, set bookmarks, etc. And this application is called &lt;strong&gt;vinagre&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Spanish for vinegar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wine and Vinegar &amp;ndash; nice :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software Libre has opened up the world to developers from outside the West Coast of the US &amp;ndash; we now have people from all over the world &amp;ldquo;scratching their itch&amp;rdquo;. For me this is one of the strongest assets of Linux and gives me a &amp;ldquo;warm inner glow&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://pipka.org/blog/2009/03/12/iceland-software-resellers-being-screwed-by-disappearing-clients-and-licensing-contracts/&#34;&gt;Pia&amp;rsquo;s post&lt;/a&gt; about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://smari.yaxic.org/blag/2009/03/06/microsoft-skull-fucks-icelands-economy-contracts-syphilis/&#34;&gt;situation in Iceland&lt;/a&gt; WRT to Micro$oft and Software Libre &amp;ndash; maybe there will be a silver lining to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://theautomaticearth.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;dire current financial situation&lt;/a&gt;. And the references to skulls and f!!cking made me smile, remembering the curses the old Warrant Officer used to give us in the army &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;Cadet Fred if you don&amp;rsquo;t get your sh!t together I will personally come and rip your bl!!dy head off and skull-f!ck you in the eyes. What are you folding your arms for &amp;ndash; only pregnant women and p!!fters fold their arms. Did you forget to get dressed when you got out of the rack this morning? Did you shave? Yes? What did you use &amp;ndash; a brick? Cadet Mary &amp;ndash; did you also forget to iron your uniform this morning? Don&amp;rsquo;t call me Sir, I work for a living. Everyone else down and give me 50, remind Cadet Mary to iron her uniform in the morning. DID I SAY YOU BAGS OF SH!T COULD LET GO OF YOUR RIFLES? DON&amp;rsquo;T YOU DARE VOMIT ON MY PARADE GROUND..&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; Someone forgot to tell him about PC :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert English language Ubuntu to Spanish</title>
      <link>http://blog2.snowfrog.net/2008/01/30/convert-english-language-ubuntu-to-spanish/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog2.snowfrog.net/2008/01/30/convert-english-language-ubuntu-to-spanish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To convert an Ubuntu installed with English to Spanish, install the following packages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;language-pack-es&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;language-pack-es-base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;language-pack-gnome-es&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;language-pack-gnome-es-base&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;language-support-es&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manpages-es&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;manpages-es-extra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here it is as one long line, for copying and pasting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;sudo aptitude install language-pack-es language-pack-es-base language-pack-gnome-es language-pack-gnome-es-base language-support-es manpages-es manpages-es-extra&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See also:  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guia-ubuntu.org/index.php?title=Acentos_y_car%C3%A1cteres_especiales&#34;&gt;Acentos y carácteres especiales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>